Guide to the Felix Adler Papers
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
- Series II: Classified Papers
  - Subseries II.2. General Classification (200)
    - 203 Ethical Education
      - The Education of Feelings--Notes on Chapter XI (Writz) (Authority, Punishment, Etc.) (Box 38, Folder 3)
      - Religious Education (Box 38, Folder 4)
      - Universities--Addresses (Box 38, Folder 5)
    - 203.01 Adult Moral Education
      - Change in the philosophy of life, 1914 January 28 (Box 38, Folder 1)
      - Adult Ethical Education (Box 38, Folder 1)
      - Adult Ethics Group Meetings (Box 38, Folder 1)
      - Adult Philosophical Education (Box 38, Folder 1)
      - Heads of the Paper on Adult Moral Education (Box 38, Folder 1)
      - The New Department of Ethical Education for Adults (Box 38, Folder 1a)
      - Adult Education for Manual Workers (Box 38, Folder 1a)
      - The Case System of Ethics (Lazarus) (Box 38, Folder 1a)
      - Problems of Religious Education (Box 38, Folder 1a)
      - Ethical Education in the Adult Period of Life (Box 38, Folder 1a)
      - Class for the study of my ethical philosophy of Life (Box 38, Folder 1a)
      - Tuesday Evening Class (Box 38, Folder 1a)
      - Adult Workmen's Education (Box 38, Folder 1a)
    - 203.02 Discipline
      (For Oxford Lectures on Culture, see 602, 1-4)
      - Discipline and Freedom (Box 38, Folder 2)
      - Student Self Government (Box 38, Folder 2)
    - 203.03 Culture (Box 38, Folder 1)
    - 203.04 Psychology (Box 39)
      - The Psychology of Number (McClellen &Dewey) (Box 39, Folder 1)
      - Farrington (The Problem of Personality) (Box 39, Folder 1)
      - Adolescence (Hall and Burnham} (Box 39, Folder 1)
      - Titchener's Experimental Psychology (Box 39, Folder 1)
      - Animal Psychology (Brehn) (Box 39, Folder 1)
      - Imagination (Angell) (Box 39, Folder 1)
      - Psychological Logic (Box 39, Folder 1)
      - Dynamic Psychology (Woodworth) (Box 39, Folder 1)
      - The Psychological Basis of the Notion of Unity (Box 39, Folder 1)
      - Lectures on Psychology (Angell) (Box 39, Folder 1)
      - The concept of adjustment (Box 39, Folder 1)
      - Memorandum on Maladjustment (Box 39, Folder 1)
      - Everett Dean Martin’s Psychology (Box 39, Folder 2)
      - Muensterberg (Psychology and Life) (Box 39, Folder 2)
      - Small and Vincent (notes) (Box 39, Folder 2)
      - Psychology of Character (Levy) (Box 39, Folder 2)
      - Psychology of Religion (Leuba) (Box 39, Folder 2)
      - Small's "psychical relations of society and solitude” (Box 39, Folder 2)
      - Nahlowsky on the Feelings (Box 39, Folder 2)
      - What is Normal? (Box 39, Folder 3)
      - The psychology of Gratitude (Box 39, Folder 3)
      - Psychology and Ethics (note) (Box 39, Folder 3)
      - Notes on Feeling (Box 39, Folder 3)
      - The relation of psychology to ethics (Box 39, Folder 3)
      - Psychology of Theistic belief (Box 39, Folder 3)
      - The Intellectual Feelings (Nahlowsky) (Box 39, Folder 3)
      - Psychology of Insanity (Hart) (Box 39, Folder 3)
      - Dr. R’s Theory and Method (Box 39, Folder 3)
      - Psychology of Crowds (Box 39, Folder 3)
      - Psychological Types (Jung) (Box 39, Folder 3)
    - 203.05 Berlin Lectures
      - Lectures (Box 39, Folder 1)
    - 203.06 Education (Miscellaneous)
      - Notes…liberal education (Box 39, Folder 1)
      - Memo…General Education Board Educational philosophy (Box 39, Folder 1)
      - Ideals of Public Education in America (Box 39, Folder 1)
      - The English Public Schools (Box 39, Folder 1)
      - Workingmen’s Colleges (Box 39, Folder 1)
      - Pedagogical Seminary (Adolescence) (Box 39, Folder 1)
      - Sphere and Scope of the Teacher of Economics (Box 39, Folder 1)
      - Notes (Box 39, Folder 1)
      - The Idea of Freedom in Moral Education (Box 39, Folder 1)
      - Outline of 6 Lectures on the Education Ideal (Box 39, Folder 1)
      - Memo (Box 39, Folder 1)
      - Culture Epochs &c. (Rein) (Box 39, Folder 2)
      - Education in the United States (Butler) (Box 39, Folder 2)
      - Object Lessons (Box 39, Folder 2)
      - Rein’s Arithmetic (Box 39, Folder 2)
      - Education (Sketch of Address) (Box 39, Folder 2)
      - Education from a National Standpoint (Box 39, Folder 2)
      - Fichte’s Scheme of National Education (Box 39, Folder 2)
      - Education in the United States (Harris) (Box 39, Folder 2)
      - Notes for address on self-culture (Box 39, Folder 3)
      - Philadelphia address on ethical self-education (Box 39, Folder 3)
      - Organic Education (Lecture) (Box 39, Folder 3)
      - Self-Education (Box 39, Folder 3)
    - 204 Ethical School
      - Miscellaneous Notes on
        - Notes taken at the Meetings of (Box 39, Folder 1)
        - The Ethical School, 1877-78 (notebook) (Box 39, Folder 1)
        - Minutes of Faculty Meeting, 1932 (Box 39, Folder 1)
        - Memorandum for the City (Box 39, Folder 1)
        - Memorandum..publications by the School (Box 39, Folder 1)
        - Alumni proposal (Box 39, Folder 1)
        - La. republique de Platon (Box 39, Folder 1)
        - Plan of government (Box 39, Folder 1)
        - Comments by Lewis on Briggs' Report (Box 39, Folder 1)
        - Tales from Talmud (Box 39, Folder 1)
        - School of Applied Ethics (Box 39, Folder 1)
        - School of Applied Ethics Prospectus (Box 39, Folder 1)
        - Chorus work (Box 39, Folder 1)
        - Statement (Box 39, Folder 1)
        - The School (Box 39, Folder 1)
        - Aims of the School (Box 39, Folder 1)
        - The Ethical School and Others (Box 39, Folder 1)
        - The School Assemblies (Box 39, Folder 1)
        - Impressions of Music Work at the School (Box 39, Folder 1)
        - Course of Study for the Elementary School (Box 39, Folder 1)
        - Constitution of the Fieldston School (Box 39, Folder 1)
        - Memorandum for the School (Box 39, Folder 1)
        - Statement for ProGries (Box 39, Folder 1)
        - Notes for Meeting at Miss Parsons' (Box 39, Folder 1)
        - Notes on Elliot’s Questions (Box 39, Folder 1)
        - Memorandum (Box 39, Folder 1)
        - Ethical Movement and education (Box 39, Folder 1)
        - Proposed Gold Medal for Excellence (Box 39, Folder 1)
        - Relation of the Ethical Ideal to the School (Box 39, Folder 1)
        - Fieldston School Directory (Box 39, Folder 2)
        - Notes relating to the School (Box 39, Folder 2)
        - Meeting with History Department (Adler) (Box 39, Folder 2)
        - Teaching of history in the Ethical Culture Schools (Box 39, Folder 2)
        - Reasons for fixing my home at Fieldston (Box 39, Folder 2)
        - Fieldston School (Donors of the Million Dollar Fund) (Box 39, Folder 2)
        - Dedication of Fieldston School (Box 39, Folder 2)
        - Workingmen’s School (Box 39, Folder 2)
        - Ethical School (Box 39, Folder 2)
        - How Fieldston Differs from other schools (Box 39, Folder 2)
        - Notes on the School (Box 39, Folder 2)
        - General Plan of the School (Box 39, Folder 2)
        - School Conference (Box 39, Folder 2)
        - Committee on History Work of the School (Box 39, Folder 3)
        - Fraternity &Sorority in the School (Box 39, Folder 3)
        - Normal Report (Box 39, Folder 3)
        - Fraternity of Youths School (Box 39, Folder 3)
        - Notes on Students' Final Exam Papers (Box 39, Folder 3)
        - Notes on the School (Box 39, Folder 3)
        - Pamphlet on the School (Box 39, Folder 3)
        - Address on the School (Box 39, Folder 3)
      - Fieldston Seminars (Box 40, Folder 4-8)
    - 204a Ethical School--Addresses to
      - Points relating to the school (Box 40, Folder 1)
      - Addresses, 1922 (Box 40, Folder 1)
      - Memorandum for the words to the graduates (Box 40, Folder 1)
      - 5 graduations, 1985, 1911, 1929, 1930, 1932 (Box 40, Folder 1)
      - Memorandum--Balance (Box 40, Folder 1)
      - School Assemblies (Box 40, Folder 1)
      - Thanksgiving Address, 1931 (Box 40, Folder 1)
      - Talk to Lower School, 1929 (Box 40, Folder 1)
      - Memorandum on talk to the School, 1932, 1913 (Box 40, Folder 1)
      - Address on “Religious teacher” to High School (Box 40, Folder 1)
      - Words for the Graduation (Box 40, Folder 1)
      - Talk to the High School (Box 40, Folder 1)
      - Dinner of Nip-Nixon Club (Box 40, Folder 1)
      - Address to Normal Students (Box 40, Folder 1)
      - Talk with Gamma and Delta Classes on Organization (Box 40, Folder 1)
      - Exercises in the Meeting Hall at Fieldston (Box 40, Folder 1)
      - Address to the High School (My Vocation) (Box 40, Folder 1)
      - Address to the Children (Box 40, Folder 1)
      - 2 other addresses (notes) (Box 40, Folder 1)
      - Commencement address-Vocation (Box 40, Folder 1)
    - 204.01 Ethical School--High School
      - Character study' (Box 40, Folder 1)
      - Ethics teaching in high school (Box 40, Folder 1)
      - School course in ethics (Box 40, Folder 1)
      - Advanced Ethics classes for girls (Box 40, Folder 1)
      - For the German Department (Box 40, Folder 1)
      - General Character of High School Body (Box 40, Folder 1)
      - Address to High School, 1923, 1924 (Box 40, Folder 1)
      - A Branch High School for Girls (Box 40, Folder 1)
      - Ethics Course in the High School (Box 40, Folder 1)
      - Conversation with Mr. Smith (Box 40, Folder 1)
      - Meaning of the word “Leader” as applied to pupils of the school (Box 40, Folder 1)
      - Outline of High School Course in Ethics (Box 40, Folder 1)
      - Moral Instruction (note) (Box 40, Folder 1)
    - 204.02 Ethical School--Preprofessional School
      - Prevocational. School for Girls (Box 40, Folder 1)
      - Additional notes on Girls' School (Box 40, Folder 1)
      - Prevocational School of Commerce (Box 40, Folder 1)
      - Outline of course in history (Box 40, Folder 1)
      - On the prevocational girls' school (Box 40, Folder 1)
      - History Course (Box 40, Folder 1)
      - Preprofessional idea applied to Teaching Business School (Box 40, Folder 1)
      - Commercial High School (Box 40, Folder 1)
      - Preprofesstonel School for Women (Box 40, Folder 1)
      - Girls School (Box 40, Folder 1)
      - School of Law (Box 40, Folder 1)
      - Huntington Emerson's Plea for Efficiency (Box 40, Folder 1a)
      - The Art High School (Box 40, Folder 1a)
      - English Arts High School course (Box 40, Folder 1a)
      - Notes on art teaching (Box 40, Folder 1a)
      - Letter on Arts High School (Lewis) (Box 40, Folder 1a)
      - Notes on Prevocational school for religious teachers (Box 40, Folder 1a)
      - The new Educational expierment (Box 40, Folder 1a)
      - Distinction between Vocational and Prevocational (Box 40, Folder 1a)
      - Virtues and Vices of Different Vocations (Box 40, Folder 1a)
      - Preprofessional School of Religious Teachers (Box 40, Folder 1a)
      - Preprofessional Idea Applied to Teaching (Box 40, Folder 1a)
      - Preprofessional School for Women (Box 40, Folder 1a)
      - Difficult of Applying Vocational Idea to Manual Labor (Box 40, Folder 1a)
      - Is it Worthwhile? (Box 40, Folder 1a)
    - 204.02 Ethical School--Business School
      - The Business School (Box 40, Folder 1b)
      - Prevocational School of Business (Box 40, Folder 1b)
      - Harvard Business College (Box 40, Folder 1b)
      - Ethics in the Business School (Box 40, Folder 1b)
    - 204.03 Ethical School--History Teaching (Box 41)
      - Conferences (Box 41, Folder 1)
      - History Teaching and History Notes
        - History Notes (Box 41, Folder 2)
        - History (Box 41, Folder 2)
        - Additional Notes on History (Box 41, Folder 2)
        - University history Course (Box 41, Folder 2)
        - The Value of History (Box 41, Folder 2)
        - Introduction to the Study of History (Lenglois and Seignobos) (Box 41, Folder 2)
        - Eggleston’s “Beginners of a Nation” (Box 41, Folder 2)
        - Outlines of History (Box 41, Folder 2)
        - Preliminary Outline of Commercial History (Box 41, Folder 3)
        - Teaching of American History (Box 41, Folder 3)
        - Teaching of English History (Box 41, Folder 3)
        - Teaching of English History to Americans (Box 41, Folder 3)
        - Notes on Uses of History (Box 41, Folder 3)
        - History Dept. in Relation to Girls' Schools (Box 41, Folder 3)
        - Plan of the School (Box 41, Folder 3)
        - Teaching of History (10 Items) (Box 41, Folder 3)
        - Method of History Teaching (Box 41, Folder 3)
        - Thoughts on History Teaching (Box 41, Folder 3)
        - The History Department (Box 41, Folder 3)
        - Teaching Political history Through Personalities (Box 41, Folder 3)
        - Course in Industrial History for Advanced Students (Box 41, Folder 3)
        - Notes (Box 41, Folder 3)
    - 204.04 Ethical School--Ethics Teaching
      - Essay on Moral Instruction in the French Schools (Box 41, Folder 1)
      - Teaching of Temperance (Box 41, Folder 1)
      - Value of the Study of Nature (Box 41, Folder 1)
      - Problem of Ethical Teaching in the High School" (Box 41, Folder 1)
      - Ethical Education for Adolescents (Box 41, Folder 1)
      - Children's Experiences (Box 41, Folder 1)
      - Conversation with Dr. Adler (Box 41, Folder 1)
      - "Moral imperative" (Box 41, Folder 1)
      - Certain Chief Heeds in the Course of Moral Instruction (Box 41, Folder 1)
      - Miss Spofford’s Ethical Lessons (Box 41, Folder 1)
      - Ethical Teaching (Box 41, Folder 1)
      - Training Necessary for the Ethical Life (Box 41, Folder 1)
      - Moral Instruction Courses (Box 41, Folder 1)
      - The Old Testament for the High School (Box 41, Folder 1)
      - The Religious Training of Children (Box 41, Folder 1)
      - How Children Become Moral (Box 41, Folder 1)
      - Character Training (Box 41, Folder 1)
      - The Moral Aim of Object Lessons (Box 41, Folder 1)
      - Plan of Teaching as Sketched for R.Dewey (Box 41, Folder 1a)
      - Ethical and Religious Education (Seminar Meetings) (Box 41, Folder 1a)
      - Spiritual Plan of Education in General (Box 41, Folder 1a)
      - Modifications of the Ethics Teaching (Box 41, Folder 1a)
      - Principal Points – 7 stations (Box 41, Folder 1a)
      - The Bible in Ethics Teaching (Box 41, Folder 1a)
      - Ethical and Religious Education (Box 41, Folder 1a)
      - Sketch of a Course for Adolescent Girls (Box 41, Folder 1a)
      - Suggestions to Mr. Cooley (Box 41, Folder 1b)
      - Notes for the 28th (Box 41, Folder 1b)
      - Notes (Box 41, Folder 1b)
      - Seminar for training ethics teachers (Box 41, Folder 1b)
      - Subjects for Advanced Students (Box 41, Folder 1b)
      - Religious Training of Children (Box 41, Folder 1b)
      - Teaching of Ethics in College (Box 41, Folder 1b)
      - Professional of the Ethics Teacher (Box 41, Folder 1b)
      - Examinations to test Moral Instruction (Box 41, Folder 1b)
      - Civics Teaching (Box 41, Folder 1b)
      - Course of study for M (Box 41, Folder 1b)
      - “Unless Ye Become as Little Children” (Box 41, Folder 1b)
      - Outline of the Ethics Statement (Box 41, Folder 1b)
      - Ethics Teaching in the School (Box 41, Folder 1b)
      - Certain Points (Box 41, Folder 1b)
      - The Child and Religious (Box 41, Folder 1b)
      - Preparation for Citizenship in the School (Box 41, Folder 1b)
      - Summary of main points in the plan of ethical and religious education (Box 41, Folder 1b)
      - The Ethics Course (Box 41, Folder 1c)
      - The Revised Ethics Course (Box 41, Folder 1c)
      - Plan of 2nd Volume on Moral Instruction (Box 41, Folder 1c)
      - Use of Bible in Ethics Teaching (Box 41, Folder 1c)
      - Ethical and Religious Education (Box 41, Folder 1c)
      - Ethical Ideal in the School (Box 41, Folder 1c)
      - Theory and Method of Education for Spiritual life (Box 41, Folder 1c)
      - Outline of Ethics Statement (Box 41, Folder 1c)
      - Outline of Ethics Treatment (Box 41, Folder 1c)
      - Answer to Miss H’s request for help in a course of Ethical Study (Box 41, Folder 1c)
      - Sketch of Ground to be Covered by an Additional Class in Ethics (Box 41, Folder 1c)
      - Memorandum on the Ethics Course (Box 41, Folder 1c)
      - Notes on the Ethics Course (2) (Box 41, Folder 1c)
      - Scheme of Moral Education (Leuba) (Box 41, Folder 1d)
      - Scheme of lessons for Ethical Classes (Box 41, Folder 1d)
      - Course in Moral Instruction for the Latin Class (Box 41, Folder 1d)
      - Ethics Test (Box 41, Folder 1d)
      - Gould’s Moral Lessons (Box 41, Folder 1d)
      - Topics for the Ethics classes (Box 41, Folder 1d)
      - Principles and methods of moral education (Box 41, Folder 1d)
    - 204.04 Ethical School--Sunday School
      - Problem of Sunday school (Box 41, Folder 2)
      - Concerning the Sunday School (Box 41, Folder 2)
      - Children's Sunday Services (Box 41, Folder 2)
      - The Sunday School (Box 41, Folder 2)
      - How to teach the ethical and Religious Ideal in different periods of life (Box 41, Folder 2)
      - Stories - 3 Kopecks, Fox and Fishes (Box 41, Folder 2)
      - Fairy Tales (Box 41, Folder 2)
      - Responses (Box 41, Folder 2)
      - Playlet – 13 states (Box 41, Folder 2)
      - Story of my Greatest Hero (Box 41, Folder 2)
      - Conversation on Religious Pedagogy (Box 41, Folder 2)
      - Training for Citizenship (Box 41, Folder 2)
      - Sunday School lessons (notebook) (Box 41, Folder 2)
    - 204.04 Ethical School--Moral Instruction of Children (Manuscript of Book)
      - Interview with Miss Peck (Box 41, Folder 3)
      - The School course in Ethics (Box 41, Folder 3)
      - Moral Instruction of' Children (Box 41, Folder 3)
    - 204.05 Ethical School--English Teaching
      - Notes…last conference on style (Box 41, Folder 1)
      - Third conference with English Department (Box 41, Folder 1)
      - Dr. Adler conference with English Department, 1929 October 10 (Box 41, Folder 1)
      - Conferences with English and other departments (Box 41, Folder 1)
      - Note for Last conference on style (Box 41, Folder 1)
      - Conference with English Department (Box 41, Folder 1)
      - The next English Conference (Box 41, Folder 1)
      - Notes on Compositions-7th Grade (Box 41, Folder 1)
      - English Reading (Box 41, Folder 1)
    - 204.05 Ethical School--Studies in English
      - Suggestions on letter writing (Box 41, Folder 2)
      - English notes (Box 41, Folder 2)
      - Remarks on English (Box 41, Folder 2)
      - Paralyzing Effect of Noble Language (Box 41, Folder 2)
      - Note on the short story (Box 41, Folder 2)
      - Sentence Plans (Box 41, Folder 2)
      - Definition (Box 41, Folder 2)
      - Literary Language end common speech (Box 41, Folder 2)
      - Style of Carlyle, etc. (Box 41, Folder 2)
      - Translations from Latin and German: "In Praise of Folly" and "Sneewitchen” (Box 41, Folder 2)
      - Quotations (Box 41, Folder 3)
      - Grammar (Box 41, Folder 4)
      - Style (Sentence construction, style, etc.) (Box 41, Folder 5)
    - 204.06 Ethical School--Ethics Lessons
      - Ethics lesson - Of, by and for the people (Box 42, Folder 1)
      - Topics for Ethics classes (Box 42, Folder 1)
      - Students; class in Ethics (Box 42, Folder 1)
      - High School Class in Ethics, 3rd Lesson, 1901 (Box 42, Folder 1)
      - 1st Lesson with Class Beta, 1901 (Box 42, Folder 1)
      - Ethics lesson, 1902 (Box 42, Folder 1)
      - Life Problems Group (Box 42, Folder 1)
      - Ethics Lessons--High School
        - 1899-1900 (Box 42, Folder 2)
        - 1901-1902 (Box 42, Folder 3)
        - 1902-1903, 1903-1904 (Box 42, Folder 4)
        - 1904-1904 (Box 42, Folder 5)
      - Ethics Lessons--Advanced (Box 42, Folder 6)
      - Ethics Lessons--New Testament (Box 42, Folder 7)
    - 204.07 Ethical School--School Festivals
      - The great religious festivals (Box 42, Folder 1)
      - Talks on Thanksgiving (4) (Box 42, Folder 1)
      - Memo on Thanksgiving (Box 42, Folder 1)
      - The Festivals and the School (Box 42, Folder 1)
      - Winter Festival in the School (Box 42, Folder 1)
      - All Souls Celebration (Box 42, Folder 1)
      - Christmas and War Years (Box 42, Folder 1)
      - Thanksgiving Day (Box 42, Folder 1)
      - Notes for Miss Vucden (Box 42, Folder 1)
      - Columbus Day (Box 42, Folder 1)
      - Responses (Bresden) (Box 42, Folder 1)
      - Subjects for Graduation Program (Box 42, Folder 1)
    - 204.08 Ethical School--Ethics Manual or Vade Mecum
      - First Sketch of a Breviary of Ethical Religion (Box 42, Folder 1)
      - Notes for Monday Meetings (Box 42, Folder 1)
      - Breviary and Encheiridion (Box 42, Folder 1)
      - Reflections-Vade Mecum for the young (Box 42, Folder 1)
      - Notes for the manual (Box 42, Folder 1)
      - Manual for the Young (Box 42, Folder 1)
      - Vade Mecum for Graduates (Box 42, Folder 1)
      - Outline of a kind of Primer in the Ethical Philosophy of Life (Box 42, Folder 1)
      - Certain Considerations (Box 42, Folder 1)
    - 204.09 Ethical School--Addresses to Teachers
      - 16 Addresses + 8, also addresses to Horace Mann teachers (Box 42, Folder 1)
    - 204.09 Ethical School--Round Table talks with Teachers (Box 42, Folder 2)
    - 205 Letters (Box 42)
      (Letters original filed in Folders 205-1 and 205-2 have been removed and added to either the cataloged correspondence, arranged correspondence, or the typescript copies correspondence files. Letters to Mr. Lewis, Mr. Fecher, James Gutmann, and from Prof. Tomoyeds were not received.)
    - 206 Conversations (Notes of)
      - Al Black (Box 42, Folder 1)
      - Dr. Coffin (Box 42, Folder 1)
      - Dr. Dike (Box 42, Folder 1)
      - Laurence (Box 42, Folder 1)
      - Macdonald (Box 42, Folder 1)
      - Snell (Box 42, Folder 1)
      - Dr. Zacher (Box 42, Folder 1)
      - Mr. Arnett (Box 42, Folder 1)
      - Mrs. Chapin (Box 42, Folder 1)
      - Ray Stannard Eaker (Box 42, Folder 1)
      - Mr. Chubb (Box 42, Folder 1)
      - Mr. Brandeis (Box 42, Folder 1)
      - Dr. Elliott (also Dr. E and Smith) (Box 42, Folder 1)
      - Mr. Jablonower (Box 42, Folder 1)
      - Dr. Horace Friess (Box 42, Folder 1)
      - Prof. Montague (Box 42, Folder 1)
      - Mr. Robert Kahn (Box 42, Folder 1)
      - Dr. Danielis (Box 42, Folder 2)
      - Mr. Perry (Box 42, Folder 2)
      - LDB (Box 42, Folder 2)
      - Dr. Boehmke (Box 42, Folder 2)
      - Horace and James (Box 42, Folder 2)
      - James Gutmann (Box 42, Folder 2)
      - Mr. Golding (Box 42, Folder 2)
      - Prof. Fullerton (Box 42, Folder 2)
      - Mr. Hopper (Box 42, Folder 2)
      - Alvin S. Johnson (Box 42, Folder 2)
      - Prof. Fullerton (Box 42, Folder 2)
      - Mrs. S. (Box 42, Folder 2)
      - Mr. Barrows (Box 42, Folder 2)
      - Mr. Bakewell (Box 42, Folder 2)
      - Mr. Sheldon (Box 42, Folder 2)
      - Dr. Payton (Box 42, Folder 2)
      - Dr. Lindsay (Box 42, Folder 2)
      - Mr. Mox (Box 42, Folder 2)
      - Miss Moore (Box 42, Folder 2)
      - At East Hill (Box 42, Folder 2)
      - Conversations with Dr. Horace Friess on Religion and Ethics (Box 42, Folder 3)
      - Bridges (Box 42, Folder 4)
      - Buschman (Box 42, Folder 4)
      - Hart (Box 42, Folder 4)
      - Neumann (Box 42, Folder 4)
      - Dr. Elliott (Box 42, Folder 4)
      - Dr. Lowenstein (Box 42, Folder 4)
      - Dr. Vanderburg (Box 42, Folder 4)
      - Miss Drew (Box 42, Folder 4)
      - Edward King (Box 42, Folder 4)
      - Prof. Otto (Box 42, Folder 4)
      - Moore and Prof. Patten (Box 42, Folder 4)
      - Prof. Tufts (Box 42, Folder 4)
      - Tagore (Box 42, Folder 4)
      - Mr. Lewis (Box 42, Folder 4)
      - Mr. O’Dell (Box 42, Folder 4)